[Maggie]
Previously on Dead City.
- Hershel?!
- [Hershel] Mom!
[loud blast]
Name's Dillard.
- [Cockenspiel growls earnestly]
- [Dillard] That is dastardly.
That is fresh.
[Renata] Maggie. you should
bring your people here.
Everything the Croat said
about this place is true.
It is a fortress.
I need this one last thing
from you.
- So what kind of doctor are you?
- Emergency medicine.
- Can I help?
- Come on.
Once we find the Dama.
who's left to stop us?
Half of Midtown is gone.
Our work is just beginning.
[wind blowing]
[intensifying music]
[walker growling]
[knife squelching]
[music by Lee Wiley starts.
Manhattan]
♪ We'll have Manhattan ♪
♪ The Bronx and Staten Island.
too ♪
♪ It's lovely
strolling through ♪
♪ The zoo ♪
[smooth jazz music]
♪ It's very fancy ♪
♪ On old Delancey Street.
you know ♪
♪ The subway charms us so ♪
[rapid gunfire in game]
♪ When balmy breezes blow
to and fro ♪
♪ And tell me
what street compares ♪
♪ With Mott Street in July ♪
♪ Sweet pushcarts ♪
♪ Gently gliding by ♪
[smooth jazz music continues]
♪ The great big city's
a wondrous toy ♪
♪ Just made for
a girl and boy ♪
♪ We'll turn Manhattan
into an isle of joy ♪
[smooth jazz music continues]
[rapid gunfire in game]
Go on and give it a shot.
- ♪ We'll go to Yonkers ♪
- Bingo.
♪ Where true love conquers
in the wilds ♪
♪ And starve together. dear
♪ In Childs
[rapid gunfire in game]
[smooth jazz music continues]
♪ We'll go to Coney ♪
♪ And eat baloney on a roll ♪
♪ In Central Park.
we'll stroll ♪
♪ Where our first kiss.
we stole ♪
♪ Soul to soul ♪
♪ AndSouth Pacific ♪
♪ Is a terrific show.
they say ♪
♪ We both may see it close
♪ Someday ♪
♪ The city's bustle
cannot destroy ♪
- ♪ The dream of a girl ♪
- [Dillard] ♪ ...Girl and boy
♪ We'll turn Manhattan ♪
♪ Into an isle of joy ♪
- [Dillard chuckling]
- [walkers snarling]
[Dillard] I'm just warmin' up.
though.
Just. just gettin' it hot.
Just gettin' it spicy.
- [walkers snarling faintly]
- [Dillard] More to come.
[rapid gunfire in game resumes]
♪ We'll turn Manhattan ♪
♪ Into an isle of joy
[smooth jazz music fades]
[birds chirping]
[squishing]
Five minutes. honey.
Yeah. I'm almost done.
Luis said he's gonna quiz me
on this at the party.
Thanks for usin' a drop cloth
this time
instead of the tablecloth.
[Hershel chuckles]
[indistinct chattering]
Come here.
Hi.
I brought you
a little somethin'.
The last bag of French roast
from Bruegel's stash.
I'm not sure if my wife's gonna
be happier to see me or this.
- If she even recognizes you.
- [Armstrong chuckling]
I appreciate it.
I really wish
you weren't leavin'.
'Cause you're gonna
miss me so much?
- I don't like it.
- I get it.
You're worried you're
gonna lose this place.
You and Renata really
got something here.
It's made you different.
Between us gettin' captured
and almost gettin' killed.
I used to wonder what you
were like before all this.
[chuckling]
[Armstrong] Now I have some
idea.
I'ma keep my mouth shut
about what you got here. Maggie.
- You can trust me.
- I do...
- And I don't.
- [Armstrong chuckling]
Anybody on the road asks me
where I got this bag
full of beans.
I'ma tell 'em the truth.
Boston.
[snickering]
Look. I know it's your job
to protect this place. but.
even if I did tell anyone.
you'd see us rollin' in
from literally a mile away.
Luis. por favor...
Red light. everyone. red light.
You know what to do.
Away from the windows.
Andale.
[tense music]
- I'll head up.
- Right behind you.
[tense music continues]
[Dillard] [indistinct chatter]
[Negan] Renata and Maggie are
at it again.
[tense music continues]
[walkers snarling faintly]
Looks like a couple of
your friends from New Babaloo.
[tense music continues]
Haven't seen
survivors in weeks.
I wonder what the hell
they're doin' up here.
[Maggie] You see anything?
[Armstrong] No.
[Linus] The Dama
needs food.
[Reece]
We need food first!
[Linus] No. no. no.
she needs it first.
[Reece] I haven't eaten in
two days...
They're tryin' to help someone.
[Linus]
We feed her. She feeds us.
The Dama feeds our minds.
our souls.
[Dillard] Because we never
signed any notarized treaty
to join their community.
Hey. hey.
I am asking him right now.
[shushing] Stop.
[walker snarling]
Titicaca wants to know
when the sweet jams can return.
How many times I gotta ask you
to stop pretendin'
like you can talk
to those toothless freaks?
How many times do I gotta tell
you I can
decipher multiple phrases?
Desires.
[Maggie] Negan. are you there?
- [shushing]
- Okay.
Deal's a deal: stop light
goes on. so does the walkie.
See. I am a good little boy.
You got eyeballs on these guys?
It sounds like
they're over by you.
Limpy McGee and Trotter?
Yeah. What are they sayin'?
They're lookin' for food
for the Dama.
Shit. the Dama eats?
I thought she just sucked blood.
This is what
we've been waitin' for.
Don't tell me that you're drunk.
[Negan] No such thing.
Let's go get her.
- [chuckling]
- [Dillard] Okay.
Who is the Dama?
She is a big dick
who's about to get hers.
[theme music]
[walkers snarling]
[tense music]
[Negan] I gotta tell ya. man.
I never thought we were gonna
get rid of ya.
Actually wantin'
to be with my family?
- I know it's a foreign concept.
- Ouch. Well. that stings.
See? I'll tell you why.
'Cause the sad truth is.
Annie and Joshua?
They are better off without me.
The happy truth is:
I'm better off without them.
Livin' in a bar
that smells like rotting flesh.
[tense music]
Okay.
[tense music continues]
[Negan] Dama's Broadway babies!
[Linus] Who feeds us more
than merely bread?
And fills our soul
and fills our head?
Who kindles dreams o'er the day?
Whose shining brilliance
guides the way?
Who sees the future
like Nostradama?
Who indeed. but our fair Dama?
[Negan clapping]
Well. Holy Jesus.
I have taken
more poetic shits than that.
We're not here to hurt you.
[Negan] That. though?
I mean. I'm not much
of a painting guy.
but those are some
sweet-ass boobies.
These are the two
hilltops of kinship.
Together. they form
the foundation of civilized...
[Negan] No. no. no. no. no. no.
Those are boobies.
Have you ever seen
an honest to God...
- Are you done?
- [Negan] Well. no.
I mean. look. those are some
hot alien boobies.
We saw you scavenging.
We brought food.
We have more food at home
than you could eat.
We have a doctor. too.
He can set you right.
I'm headin' back
to New Babylon tomorrow.
If you'd rather come home.
there's room on my boat.
Sounds amazing.
A bunch of strangers
who wanna help us
and who don't want
anything from us?
We just want you
to tell us where the Dama is.
- That's all you have to do.
- [Dama] I saved these men.
They were injured.
Not just their bodies.
their minds.
They couldn't dream.
I fixed them.
But the first thing
that you dream is
not to let anyonestop
you from dreaming.
You stopped Hershel.
But you didn't stop me.
And you can't stop them.
Oh. yeah. I mean. however
are we gonna stop them?
Leave now. You'll live.
[Dama] But your dreams will die.
- [Armstrong] Damn it.
- You are gonna get
these boys killed!
[Dama]
"Once more unto the breach.
"dear friends. once more;
or close them all up
with our English dead."
- Go now! Please!
- [Dama] "In peace..."
Drop your weapons.
"There's nothing
so becomes a man
as modest stillness
and humility."
Please just turn around.
- [Maggie] All of you.
- [Dama] "But. when
the blast of war..."
[gunshot]
- God damn it!
- Drop your weapons!
[Dama] "Stiffen the sinews..."
[gunshots]
[Dama] "Summon up the blood..."
[dramatic music]
God. that was stupid!
[dramatic music continues]
Go.
- [Maggie] Go!
- [whimpering]
[Dama] Fight!
Fight. you coward!
[dramatic music]
There.
[dramatic music continues]
- It's over. Dama.
- [Dama] The end is
never really the end.
[rope creaks. snaps]
[Armstrong] Look out!
[bodies thudding]
[chandelier crashing]
[dramatic music continues]
[Negan groaning]
Son of a bitch. [groans]
There she goes. Get up! Hurry!
[dramatic music continues]
- [walker snarling]
- [screaming] No!
[walker growling]
- [Dama groaning]
- [walker snarling]
[dramatic music continues]
[blade squelching]
[Dama panting]
[tense music]
[Maggie panting]
[panting] You selfish swine!
Your son...
was gonna shape
the future of this city.
But you couldn't let that
happen.
You had to lure him away.
I will see Hershel again.
and when I do.
he will understand the error
of his ways.
[Negan] Sure.
Keep talkin'... Please.
[Armstrong]
You don't need to kill her.
[Negan] Oh. no.
She absolutely needs to die.
[suspenseful music]
No!
[gunshot]
[bullet whizzing]
[tense music]
[wind blowing]
[birds chirping]
[metal rattling]
[walkers growling]
[walkers growling faintly]
[Dama] Where's The Croat?
He obviously built
these for you.
Where is he?
Dead.
Th... and where
did you get these tanks?
[tense music]
Eat.
Not in here.
I can't be in here.
Why haven't you killed me yet?
[tense music continues]
[walkers snarling faintly]
Maggie...
I... I... I might have...
...underestimated you.
Maybe you are where
Hershel gets his spark.
I wanna help. Maggie.
I want this city to be restored.
It's all I've ever wanted.
This hospital was a
great start.
but you need to think bigger.
Enough of these tanks.
you can power this whole island.
We just need to talk
about it more.
So I can paint pictures for you?
So I can kill for you?
I had a vision.
I have knowledge.
Central Park used
to be farmland.
These lofts. factories...
There's an entire civilization
just waiting to be unleashed.
There is.
Maggie!
[walkers snarling]
[tense music continues]
[tray clattering]
[walkers growling]
[paper rustling]
- I don't think I'm ready yet.
- [Luis] You are.
Remember:
one breath. one motion.
[Negan] Hey!
Somebody get me a goddamn
needle. I'll do it myself!
It's just skin.
His is obviously very thin.
[skin squelching]
[Negan groaning]
[Negan sighing]
[skin squelching]
So glad I get to be. like.
your practice dummy here.
What the hell are
you even doin' here?
What does it look like?
I'm watchin' my son put a needle
through your flesh repeatedly.
Why don't you go get your son.
like.
a shot of hooch
to calm his nerves?
Just 'cause you
don't like needles.
you don't have to take
it out on him.
Oh. yeah.
Obviously. I have a real
aversion to needles.
needle dick.
Look. Sparky...
I have saved
your life multiple times.
Why are you scared of me?
Why would anyone be
weirded out by the dude who
spends all day
playing video games
in his walker bar?
I mean. how'd you even get this?
One of those empty
bottles of yours
try to jump out and bite ya?
He doesn't know?
[gentle music]
She's downstairs.
She's locked up.
She is never gonna hurt you.
I promise.
There's no need to be afraid.
I know this is wrong. but...
I think if I was there. I would
have wanted to kill her. but...
Everybody in
the room wanted that.
But I don't know if I could've.
[inhales sharply] Sometimes
I worry. you know.
when it's my time
to kill a person.
that I won't be able to do it.
Is that somethin'
you can teach me?
[music intensifies]
So realistically.
what are our options here?
What?
We really just have two?
Kill her or keep her locked
up for the rest of her life?
Or we could try
to rehabilitate her.
- You ever seen that work?
- Yeah. I have.
You think it'll work with her?
- I don't know.
- [Renata] Okay.
If we keep her locked up in
jail. we are using resources.
And I'm not just
talking about food.
If we're sayin' that she
is so dangerous that she can't
be outside of a cage.
then we need someone
to guard her to make sure
that she never gets
outta that cage
and probably another guard
guarding the first guard.
since we clearly can't
leave her alone with anyone.
Or we kill her.
And all we lose are the values
we built this community on.
[Negan] Bulllllllll shiiiiiit.
[scoffing] Excuse me?
Look. if the values
of this community are keeping
a murderer around.
then best of luck to you.
[Renata. scoffing]
I know for a fact
that you have killed innocent
people.
- Should we just kill you. too?
- [Negan] Yeah.
See. the issue here is...
I am not in your community.
See. I reside in Fuck-you-ville.
ZIP code: Fuck you.
Nothing lasts unless you are
willing to do the most
brutal shit imaginable
to keep it. and that. my friend.
that ain't you.
You are correct. That ain't me.
And if that is a problem
for you. then congratulations.
You definitely made
the right call hiding out
in that stinky bar of yours.
Look...
you can go downstairs and kill
the lady that wanted to kill
you and Hershel or you can
listen to this lady
who's gonna get you
and Hershel killed.
[Negan] It's your call.
[tense music]
[bat knocking]
[tense music continues]
I know the Dama.
and Negan knows her. too.
We have all been
terrorized by her.
What she had the Croat do to us?
No one makes the right decision
when they're scared or angry.
And I... I am really trying
to hold the light here. Maggie.
I really am. but...
I don't know if I can.
May not have to.
She's not eating.
I was just down there
and she looks like she's been
malnourished for a while.
She keeps up this hunger strike.
she won't last for long.
Then maybe we let her
make the decision.
I mean.
if she's set on killin' herself
in the most
painful way possible.
starvin' herself to death?
I don't see anything wrong
with givin' her another option.
It doesn't have to be slow.
Just do me a favor
and drop it.
How can I drop it. okay?
If you're sayin'
I can't understand.
them. you're sayin' I'm a liar.
No. what I am saying is stop
pretendin' like
- you can understand...
- Again with the pretending.
I'm not pretending.
- I am...
- [walker snarling]
- I'm adapting.
- Jesus Christ.
- No...
- Hold on. it's okay. It's okay.
[walker growling]
- [walker snarling]
- [Dillard groans like walker]
[walker snarling]
His name is Chaz.
Hey. don't poke the bear.
[walker growling]
[Dillard groaning like a walker]
[walker groaning]
[metal rattling]
[walker growling]
- [walker snarling]
- Okay...
Poor bastard's a Jets fan.
[walker growling]
[metal rattling]
[walker snarling]
Get outta my way.
[walker growling]
[cracking]
[metal rattling]
[metal creaking]
[Negan] Move!
[thudding]
[glass shattering]
[walkers snarling]
[Dillard] Damn c'mon!
Let's go. let's go. let's go!
- [Negan] Up this way!
- [walkers snarling]
[Dillard] Move!
[tense music]
- You good?
- [walkers snarling]
[Negan sighs]
You're not funny.
[panting]
[walkers growling]
[brick thudding]
These fuckers. they have teeth.
And nails.
[thudding]
They aren't your little pets
at the bar.
They are death on two feet.
Do you hear me?
- [walkers snarling]
- Yeah.
[Negan] I can't believe
I even have to say this at all
after all these... years.
[skin squelching]
[walker snarling]
[Negan groaning]
- [Negan grunting]
- [walker snarling]
[walker roaring]
[air conditioner thudding]
[skin squelching]
[tense music]
You pull somethin'
like that again. I will chat
you up with a tire iron.
- [Dillard panting]
- [Negan groaning]
[Dillard panting]
- Hey...
- [Negan sighing]
[groaning like a walker]. that's
how deadies say "I'm sorry."
[Dillard panting]
[tense music continues]
[gentle music]
I used to be a cop.
I used to work undercover.
When you go deep. it's not you.
you know?
But it is. right?
Whoever you are. it's not.
But it has to be.
And for years.
when I went dark. it was me.
And it was someone else.
I'm holed up
in that bar for ages.
I knew I didn't understand 'em.
I had to pretend
or I would've gone crazy.
Shit. maybe I did. I don't know.
Maybe I don't
really know what is happenin'.
I do know one thing.
[gentle music]
When you play
a part for too long.
it becomes a piece
of who you are.
And no matter what. there is no
way it's ever gonna leave you.
So a part of me is always gonna
be the guy that had
to unload shipping containers
full of girls.
[somber music]
And a piece of me is always
gonna understand them.
It's fuckin' boobies.
[tense music]
I talked to the doctor.
I'm not eating.
- I will not be here.
- I know.
[tense music continues]
I stood across from Negan
when he was in a cell.
He wanted me to kill him.
and I didn't
'cause I wanted him to suffer.
I'm not gonna kill you
and I don't want you to suffer.
You aren't gettin' out of here.
okay?
But you can share the things
that you know.
You can try to make up
for what you've done.
You can change.
Take a bite.
Or don't... There's the knife.
It is your choice.
[tense music continues]
[wind gusting]
[Dillard shuts door]
[Negan] Hey... Ah?
I put 'em away.
They're in my room.
I needed... needed a break.
I think I'll be...
[clearing throat]
I'll be a little better
if they're not
down here so much. right?
Okay. yeah. I think. uh....
I think that's...
that's probably a good idea.
Hey. I was wonderin'. um...
You wanna show me how to play
that video game
you always playin'?
I mean. uh. do you want to?
You want me to?
[Negan] Get ready. my friend.
to shit a dick.
I'm about to ground your raw ass
till you moo. patty cake.
My brother. you could not hit a
cow's ass with a fuckin' banjo.
Oh. fuck you all balls.
I had you.
And a dong in the bush
is worth two in the hand.
[Negan] Uh oh!
- Come on. come on. come on!
- Uh-huh...
[Dillard] Come on. come on.
Come on. come on. come on.
come on!!!
God damn it!
[sighing] Gargle a chainsaw.
- That was... I had that shit.
- Ooh. someone is saltier
than Moby Dick's dick.
[Dillard] You know.
that's really funny.
'cause I just heard
that the blue whale's vagina is
now the second-largest pussy
in the world next to you.
Which you would probably
know somethin' about
because your mom's name
was Sheet Cake.
And every time she went to
a party. everybody got a slice.
Your mom actually
is a lovely woman.
I won't trash her.
but she should've swallowed ya.
- That's a fact. actually.
- Hey.
Margaret. what brings you
to the wrong side of the tracks?
You got a sec?
[Negan] All right.
you best keep practicin'.
[Dillard] You best bite curbs.
baby.
Pow! Pow!
Okay?
Why did you stay here?
The day we buried Ginny.
you were ready to get on a boat.
Why did you stay?
It wasn't to sit
on that couch all day. was it?
[sighing] No... No.
I thought I would
check out a Knicks game.
Could you fucking not?
Are you okay?
I don't want her
to have a choice.
[sighs]
I wanted to kill her
in that theater.
and I want to kill her now.
All right.
Why are you tellin' me?
Because you're the only
one that understands.
[somber music]
So. kill her.
This place is special.
It's the last.
best hope for any of us.
Hershel most of all.
With all the supplies
that we got from the gangs
and New Babylon and everything
that we brought down
from the Bricks?
We've got weapons. we've got
food. we've got electricity.
We're not startin' from zero
with what we know
or with what we have.
And you're one of the lessons.
- You didn't kill me. huh?
- [Maggie] I didn't.
You ever consider
that maybe I'm just one
of the extra special cases?
You aren't.
I am.
All right. so... [sighing]
You're lookin' to play
the Keep People Alive game?
I've played it
many times myself.
That game is rigged.
See.
in order to keep people alive?
You have to kill a whole bunch
of other people.
Sooner or later.
you're gonna kill the wrong
person and get all spun out.
And then you can't
kill the right person.
It is easier to steer clear.
- That's how she thinks.
- It's the truth.
[sighing] So this is it?
This is it.
You could help build something.
A sand castle in a hurricane.
You don't think maybe...
you could do something
for people after
everything you've done?
Everything I have done
was trying to help people.
I am done doin'.
[somber music continues]
That day with the Croat...
We went through something.
At least. I did.
And I thought that you did. too.
You know. I finally figured out
why he let you stick around.
You are just
as dead as his friends.
[somber music continues]
[door slamming]
How'd that go. pretty smooth?
Yeah. just like silk.
[frog croaking]
Oh. hey there. fella.
Who let you out?
Someone leave the door open
to 3-1-5 again? Check him.
Whoa. whoa. whoa.
Dude. dude. dude...
[Dillard] Dude...
[match cracking]
- Okay?
- [Negan] Yeah.
It's bad for the skin.
- I'll be outside.
- [Dillard] Appreciate it.
[dramatic music]
[mice squeaking]
[dramatic music continues]
[glass shattering]
[mice squealing]
[walker growling weakly]
[dramatic music continues]
[bird squawking]
[buzzer buzzing]
[doorbell ringing]
Hey... Look. I. uh...
I just wanted you to know
that I am not dead.
I went through some shit
that day too.
Okay.
I'm just... I'm never gonna
live in this building.
It... I don't know.
I... it's not safe.
Not safe because you can't kill
whoever you think needs
to be killed?
No. Just listen.
When I started out
with the Saviors.
we wanted to keep it small.
[Maggie] Right.
But the numbers. they didn't...
They didn't work out.
You have to have enough people
to keep enough people going.
- The Saviors...
- Listen. you don't wanna live
in a place where you have
to play executioner. right?
- That is the old world.
- No. You're wrong.
The reason the old world worked
was because there was wardens
and prison guards and judges and
cops and lawyers and the people
that made the fuckin' lunches
for the lawyers.
So you're saying more people?
A shit ton: more than the
Hilltop. more than the Saviors.
That is how you make this place
the kinda safe that you want.
Do you really think we could
bring back the old world here?
I don't know that I'd want to.
'Cause I've been tryin'
to keep this place secret.
[gentle music]
But maybe... Maybe...
But the truth is.
we have enough food.
We could triple our population
and still have enough.
And then we could train
more doctors and more engineers.
We could plow Central Park.
[gentle music continues]
Grow more food.
bring in even more people.
Ah but the thing is. you don't
want just more people. Maggie.
you want good people.
And I hate to be the one
to break it to you.
I don't know that there's a lot
of good people left.
You were a gym teacher.
And then the world changed
and people changed
because they got scared.
You take away that fear...
Alexandria... The prison...
When we had enough.
before things went bad.
people started to change
for the better.
Not all people.
Some people can't change.
Those are the people you'll have
the judges and the lawyers
and the wardens for.
[scoffing. chuckling]
You're wrong.
[gentle music continues]
I guess we'll find out.
[Renata] From the beginning.
all you've been doing is tryin'
to keep this place a secret.
The red lights. the cameras.
the window panels...
- [Maggie] I know.
- [Renata] You said that if
anyone found out
about this place.
they would kill us all
to try to steal it.
[Maggie] I know.
Okay. So has
any of that changed?
Those people would kill us
all to try to steal it.
And that is
why we need more people.
We need enough people to be
able to fight back all comers.
We do what you're proposing
and bad people could
be on our shores tomorrow.
And we'll be ready for them.
We'll have sentries posted
all along here. every point.
Anybody comin' across
this river. we can see 'em.
With our armory. we're gonna
be more prepared than they are.
But why even
entertain the notion?
This is the best that any
of us have ever had it. Maggie.
We have a pantry full of food.
A pantry that is getting less
and less full every single day
with no way to replenish it.
Winter will be here
before we know it.
and that is when people
get the most desperate.
Desperate people
are the most dangerous.
We bring in more people.
we can start
plowing Central Park.
Maggie. we have a hospital.
A hospital that is only
as good as its doctors.
We've got one doctor.
God forbid
anything should happen
to Luis before he starts
trainin' some more people.
These people coming across.
we could have more doctors.
Okay look.
I get what you're saying. I do.
I understand your argument.
but my ultimate job is
to keep people alive today.
I... I'm sorry. Maggie.
I can't do this.
Listen. Renata....
When I was in charge
at the Hilltop and the Bricks...
I thought the exact same way.
I could only concentrate
on what was in front of me.
I didn't have what we have now.
I didn't have the opportunity
to think ahead.
And I know that this goes
against everything the world
has taught us;
I know that it's scary.
But you're always saying you
can't make the best decisions
when you're scared.
Maggie. I have my little
baby niece I have to think about
[Maggie] And I have my son.
And I understand
they're safe right now.
but they're not secure.
And if we don't open up.
what kinda future
do we have for them?
I believe in you. Renata.
I believe you can keep us
alive today and tomorrow.
We have what we have right now.
and it is up to us
what we do with it.
[gentle music]
Who do we wanna be?
[gentle music continues]
[door opens]
[Renata] Hey!
[grunts]
We just wanna help you.
Will you let us do that?
Will you let us just help you.
please?
Remember what I
said at the theater?
It still stands.
[Renata] It's okay.
[gentle music continues]
[Renata] It'll be okay... okay?
[Maggie] Armstrong!
[Armstrong]
I hope you found a cab
to take you
all the way across town.
[chuckling]
How many times
we gonna say goodbye?
I know.
It's the last one. I promise.
I. uh... I was wrong before.
You can tell people
about this place.
We want people to come.
good people.
I surely will.
[Maggie]
I want you to come back.
I know that you're goin' home
to see your family. but...
I hope you'll come back.
all of you.
I appreciate it. I do. but...
I'm not comin' back here.
At least not for a while.
You're not goin' back just
for your family. are ya?
[Armstrong]
New Babylon needs me.
With the army gone.
I know things have probably
changed there and. if not.
there are a few of us who've
been waitin' on a chance
to change it.
- This is it.
- If anybody can do it. you can.
Thank you.
And once I do.
you better believe that the two
of us are gonna have a lot
to talk about.
[gentle music]
[waves splashing]
[walkers snarling]
You can tell
your drawling counterpart...
this tuna casserole
is pedestrian at best.
- What?
- I thought you might be dead.
Now I get to kill ya.
[walkers snarling]
[tense music]
- I'm armed.
- Cool.
[tense music continues]
[walkers snarling]
Help!
Someone come down here! Help!
Somebody come down here!
Help me! Help!
- Insane. right?
- Someone come down here!
No guards.
A psychopath like you?
And no one but little ol' me
to keep this place safe.
[dramatic music]
[Dama groaning]
[knife clattering]
[dramatic music continues]
[Maggie] Hey. you okay?
Once we pull that switch.
there's no turnin' back.
I know that you
have a plan to deal
with any bad people who might
be drawn our way...
[Maggie]
You're worried about the island?
It's like I told you.
No Christos. no Bruegel.
and no Croat.
What about the guy
who trained The Croat?
[Maggie] Negan has changed.
[Renata]
But it's still in him. Maggie.
And that... That's bad.
Honestly. the thing
that scares me is...
I don't know if it's bad
for them or for us.
Ain't no fun
when the rabbit's got the gun.
[music intensifies]
Ready?
Here we go.
[tense music]
[machines whirring]
[majestic music]
[tense music]
[walkers growling]
[Dama growling]
[tense music]
What do you think it means?
I think we should see.
[man whistling]
[suspenseful music]
Put your weapons down.
everyone!
Weapons down!
♪♪
I need to know
that I can trust you
if shit hits the fan.
We're going on lockdown.
With everything happening.
we can't be too careful.
♪♪
Two groups of people.
But only one can stay.
So we're gonna play a game.
♪♪